# **Done Alvin**

Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub | Hackerrank

Location: Nairobi, Kenya Email: alvindon41@gmail.com | Mobile: 0703287601

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

I am a skilled web developer with over **over one year of experience** in **HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and NodeJs**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React, and ExpressJs** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks. Besides I am also knowlegeable in UX design standards and farmiliar with Figma.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : JavaScript, HTML, CSS

**Frameworks** : React.js, Express, Node.js, SASS Libraries : Chakra, Redux, React Router **Databases** : MongoDB, PostgreSQL **Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Git

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

**CMS** 

#### Web Developer Trainer

January 2023 - May 2023

Remote

Community Web Development Training

Teaching new developers HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

: WordPress and Sanity

- Review codes for and help new developers whenever they get stuck on tasks.
- Teach new developers Git version control system.

**Frontend Intern** October 2022 - Dec 2022 Zuri Internship Remote

- Developed app sticking to design as handed over by designers.
- Colaborated with other devs, designers and project managers.
- Utilised CI/CD method in development to introduce new features.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Real Estate Landing Page**

JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Source Code

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Optimized website for speed and user experience
- Utilized **responsive design** to ensure compatibility across all devices
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

JavaScript, ReactJs, CSS using styled components **Movie App** 

Source Code

- A movie app developed by fetching data from The Movie Database
- Utilised responsive design to make the app compatible on all devices
- · Deployed on netlify

#### **CRUD Project Management App**

JavaScript, ReactJs, Firebase, Tailwind, React Query

Source Code

- A task management web app for a conceptual tech repair business
- A CRUD application for managing projects
- Utilised ReactJs and React Query for state management for the client side of the application
- Utilised Firebase for backend services

# **EDUCATION**

# Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelor of Science Industrial Chemistry

# Sawagongo High School

Kenya Secondary Certificate Examination

Juja, Kiambu, Kenya Sept 2013 – Nov 2017

Siaya, Kenya Feb 2009 – Nov 2012

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Google UX Design Professional Certificate

## REFERENCES

## **Mildred Ochieng**

- Community Web Development Training Lead
- 0705960799